https://www.genusplc.com/services/privacy-policy/

Social Media
This Privacy Policy explains what we do with your personal data. It describes how we collect, use and process your personal data, and how, in doing so, we comply with our legal obligations to you. Your privacy is important to us, and we are committed to protecting and safeguarding your data privacy rights.
This Privacy Policy applies to the personal data of Customers, Distributors, Suppliers, Job Applicants, Website Users and other people whose personal data may be processed, such as the emergency contacts and dependents of our Employees. To be clear, if you are an Employee, you should refer to the Genus Employee Privacy Policy which is available on Helix, the Genus intranet.
This Privacy Policy applies to personal data processed by Genus plc or an Associated Company ("Genus" or "us"). For the purpose of applicable data protection legislation (including but not limited to the General Data Protection Regulation (Regulation (EU) 2016/679) (the "GDPR"), the company responsible for your personal data can be found here. Please note that references to “Genus” should be read as “PIC” or “ABS” as relevant depending on which Genus Associated Company you are interacting with.
It is important to point out that we may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time. Please just visit this page if you want to stay up to date, as we will post any changes here.
If you are dissatisfied with any aspect of our Privacy Policy, you may have legal rights. We have described these as well where relevant.
This Privacy Policy applies in relevant countries throughout our European network. Different countries may approach data privacy in slightly different ways and so we may also have country-specific parts to this Privacy Policy. You can find country-specific terms for your jurisdiction below. This allows us to ensure that we're complying with all applicable data privacy protections.
Read the full policy in English
Read the full Privacy Policy in French
Read the full Privacy Policy in German
Read the full Privacy Policy in Italian
Read the full Privacy Policy in Polish
Read the full Privacy Policy in Romanian
Read the full Privacy Policy in Spanish
What kind of personal data do we collect?
CUSTOMER DATA: If you are a Customer, we need to collect and use information about you in the course of providing you services.
If you would like a more detailed description of the personal data that we collect in this way, please click here.
To the extent that you access our website we will also collect certain data from you. If you would like more information about this, please click here.
DISTRIBUTOR DATA: We need a small amount of information from our Distributors to ensure that things run smoothly. We need contact details of relevant individuals at your organisation so that we can communicate with you. We also need other information such as your bank details so that we can pay for the services you provide.
If you would like a more detailed description of the personal data that we collect about you, please click here.
To the extent that you access our website we will also collect certain data from you. If you would like more information about this, please click here.
SUPPLIER DATA: We need a small amount of information from our Suppliers to ensure that things run smoothly. We need contact details of relevant individuals at your organisation so that we can communicate with you. We also need other information such as your bank details so that we can pay for the services you provide.
If you would like a more detailed description of the personal data that we collect about you, please click here.
To the extent that you access our website we will also collect certain data from you. If you would like more information about this, please click here.
JOB APPLICANTS: Depending on the relevant circumstances and applicable local laws and requirements, we may collect personal data from you to enable us to engage in a recruitment exercise.
If you would like a more detailed description of the personal data that we collect about you, please click here.
To the extent that you access our website we will also collect certain data from you. If you would like more information about this, please click here.
PEOPLE WHOSE DATA WE RECEIVE FROM JOB APPLICANTS AND STAFF, SUCH AS REFEREES AND EMERGENCY CONTACTS: We only ask for very basic contact details, so that we can get in touch with you either for a reference or because you’ve been listed as an emergency contact for one of our Staff members.
If you would like a more detailed description of the personal data that we collect about you, please click here.
WEBSITE USERS: We collect a limited amount of data from our Website Users which we use to help us to improve your experience when using our website and to help us manage the services we provide. This includes information such as how you use our website, the frequency with which you access our website, and the times that our website is most popular.
If you would like to find out more information about what data we collect about you when you visit our website, please click here.
A number of elements of the personal data we collect from you are required to enable us to fulfil our contractual duties to you or to others. Other items may simply be needed to ensure that our relationship can run smoothly.
Depending on the type of personal data in question and the grounds on which we may be processing it, should you decline to provide us with such data, we may not be able to fulfil our contractual requirements or, in extreme cases, may not be able to continue with our relationship.
For details of the legal bases that we rely on to be able to use and process your personal data, please click here.
How do we collect your personal data?
CUSTOMER DATA: There are three main ways in which we collect your personal data:
Directly from you; and
From third parties; and
From other limited sources.
If you would like to know more about how we collect your personal data, please click here.
DISTRIBUTOR DATA: There are three main ways in which we collect your personal data:
Directly from you; and
From third parties; and
From other limited sources.
If you would like to know more about how we collect your personal data, please click here.
To the extent that you access our website or read or click on an email from us, we may also collect certain data automatically or through you providing it to us. For more information please click here.
SUPPLIER DATA: We collect your personal data during the course of our work with you.
To the extent that you access our website or read or click on an email from us, we may also collect certain data automatically or through you providing it to us. For more information please click here.
JOB APPLICANTS: There are three main ways in which we collect your personal data:
Directly from you; and
From third parties; and
From other limited sources.
If you would like to know more about how we collect your personal data, please click here.
To the extent that you access our website or read or click on an email from us, we may also collect certain data automatically or through you providing it to us. For more information please click here.
PEOPLE WHOSE DATA WE RECEIVE FROM STAFF, SUCH AS REFEREES AND EMERGENCY CONTACTS: We collect your contact details only where a member of our Staff puts you down as their emergency contact or where a Job Applicant gives them to us in order for you to serve as a referee.
WEBSITE USERS: We collect your data automatically via cookies when you visit our website, in line with cookie settings in your browser. If you would like to find out more about cookies, including how we use them and what choices are available to you, please click here.
How do we use your personal data?
CUSTOMER DATA: We use your personal data is to ensure that the contractual arrangements between us can properly be implemented so that the relationship can run smoothly.
For more details on how we use your personal data, please click here.
DISTRIBUTOR DATA: The main reasons for using your personal data are to ensure that the contractual arrangements between us can properly be implemented so that the relationship can run smoothly, and to comply with legal requirements.
For more details on how we use your personal data, please click here.
SUPPLIER DATA: The main reasons for using your personal data are to ensure that the contractual arrangements between us can properly be implemented so that the relationship can run smoothly, and to comply with legal requirements.
For more details on how we use your personal data, please click here.
JOB APPLICANTS: We use your personal data to ensure that we can carry out an appropriate recruitment exercise, to carry out equal opportunities monitoring, and to comply with legal requirements.
For more details on how we use your personal data, please click here.
PEOPLE WHOSE DATA WE RECEIVE FROM JOB APPLICANTS AND STAFF, SUCH AS REFEREES AND EMERGENCY CONTACTS: We may also use referees' personal data to contact them in relation to applications made by Job Applicants. We use the personal details of a Job Applicant or Staff member's emergency contacts in the case of an accident or emergency affecting that Job Applicant or member of Staff.
For more details on how we use your personal data, please click here.
WEBSITE USERS: We use your data to help us to improve your experience of using our website.
If you would like to find out more about cookies, including how we use them and what choices are available to you, please click here.
Please note that communications to and from Staff including emails may be reviewed as part of internal or external investigations or litigation.
Who do we share your personal data with?
CUSTOMER DATA: We may share your information with any of our group companies and associated third parties such as our service providers.
If you would like to see a list of who we may share your personal data with, please click here.
DISTRIBUTOR DATA: Unless you specify otherwise, we may share your information with any of our group companies and associated third parties such as our service providers and organisations to whom we provide services.
If you would like to see a list of who we may share your personal data with, please click here.
SUPPLIER DATA: Unless you specify otherwise, we may share your information with any of our group companies and associated third parties such as our service providers and organisations to whom we provide services.
If you would like to see a list of who we may share your personal data with, please click here.
JOB APPLICANTS: Unless you specify otherwise, we may share your information with any of our group companies and associated third parties such as our service providers and organisations to whom we provide services.
If you would like to see a list of who we may share your personal data with, please click here.
PEOPLE WHOSE DATA WE RECEIVE FROM JOB APPLICANTS AND STAFF, SUCH AS REFEREES AND EMERGENCY CONTACTS: Unless you specify otherwise, we may share your information with any of our group companies and associated third parties such as our service providers and organisations to whom we provide services.
If you would like to see a list of who we may share your personal data with, please click here.
WEBSITE USERS: Unless you specify otherwise, we may share your information with providers of web analytics services, marketing automation platforms and social media services to make sure any advertising you receive is targeted to you.
How do we safeguard your personal data?
We care about protecting your information. That's why we put in place appropriate measures that are designed to prevent unauthorised access to, and misuse of, your personal data.
For more information on the procedures we put in place, please click here.
How long do we keep your personal data for?
We will ordinarily process your data throughout the course of our interactions and will then generally retain it for an appropriate amount of time after we have parted ways, depending on local law requirements and our legitimate business and risk-management needs. One this period of time had expired, we will Delete your personal data from our systems unless we believe in good faith that the law or other regulation requires us to preserve it (for example, because of our obligations to tax authorities or in connection with any anticipated litigation).
For more information on our policy for the retention of personal data, please click here.
How can you access, amend or take back the personal data that you have given to us?
Even if we already hold your personal data, you still have various rights in relation to it. To get in touch about these, please contact us. We will seek to deal with your request without undue delay, and in any event in accordance with the requirements of any applicable laws. Please note that we may keep a record of your communications to help us resolve any issues which you raise.
Right to object: If we are using your data because we deem it necessary for our legitimate interests to do so, and you do not agree, you have the right to object. We will respond to your request within 30 days (although we may be allowed to extend this period in certain cases). Generally, we will only disagree with you if certain limited conditions apply.
Right to withdraw consent: Where we have obtained your consent to process your personal data for certain activities (for example, for profiling your suitability for certain roles), or consent to market to you, you may withdraw your consent at any time.
Data Subject Access Requests (DSAR): Just so it's clear, you have the right to ask us to confirm what information we hold about you at any time, and you may ask us to modify, update or Delete such information. At this point we may comply with your request or, additionally do one of the following:
we may ask you to verify your identity, or ask for more information about your request; and
where we are legally permitted to do so, we may decline your request, but we will explain why if we do so.
Right to erasure: In certain situations (for example, where we have processed your data unlawfully), you have the right to request us to "erase" your personal data. We will respond to your request within 30 days (although we may be allowed to extend this period in certain cases) and will only disagree with you if certain limited conditions apply. If we do agree to your request, we will Delete your data but will generally assume that you would prefer us to keep a note of your name on our register of individuals who would prefer not to be contacted. That way, we will minimise the chances of you being contacted in the future where your data are collected in unconnected circumstances. If you would prefer us not to do this, you are free to say so.
Right of data portability: If you wish, you have the right to transfer your data from us to another data controller. We will help with this – either by directly transferring your data for you, or by providing you with a copy in a commonly used machine-readable format.
Right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority: You also have the right to lodge a complaint with your local supervisory authority.
If you would like to know more about your rights in respect of the personal data we hold about you, please click here.
How do we store and transfer your data internationally?
For more information on the steps we take when we transfer and store your data internationally, please click here.
Who is responsible for processing your personal data on the website?
Genus controls the processing of personal data on its website(s).
If you've got any further questions, or want further details, please click here.
What are cookies and how do we use them?
A "cookie" is a bite-sized piece of data that is stored on your computer's hard drive. They are used by nearly all websites and do not harm your system. We use them to track your activity to help ensure you get the smoothest possible experience when visiting our website. We can use the information from cookies to ensure we present you with options tailored to your preferences on your next visit. We can also use cookies to analyse traffic and for advertising purposes.
If you want to check or change what types of cookies you accept, this can usually be altered within your browser settings. We also provide information about this in our Marketing preferences page on the Genus website.
If you want to find out more about cookies, including how we use them and what choices are available, please click here.
How to reject cookies
If you don’t want to receive cookies that are not strictly necessary to perform basic features of our site, you may choose to opt-out by changing your browser settings.
Most web browsers will accept cookies but if you would rather we didn’t collect data in this way you can choose to accept all or some, or reject cookies in your browser's privacy settings. However, rejecting all cookies means that you may not be able to take full advantage of all our website's features. Each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences.
For more information generally on cookies, including how to disable them, please refer to aboutcookies.org. You will also find details on how to delete cookies from your computer.
arrow
Regulatory news
Keep up to date with our RNS
Regulatory news
Results, reports and presentations
View our results, reports and presentations
Results, reports and presentations
